Okay.
It is
Very
tire.
It's beautiful.
She would have
Sorry.
I'm tired.
Have you tried it?
because we were running low on charged batteries.
Someone's not here to put them charger.
Perfect. Give me
>> Good morning. Good morning. Welcome to Consumed. Glad you're here with us
today.
We're all about being in a space and creating the time
for heaven to meet earth. And heaven is where God's presence is.
Amen. >> So heaven doesn't have to be far away.
There's at least uh three or four mountains in the Old Testament referred
to as the mountain of God. Well, is that a mistake? Is
that a contradiction? No. They just called it the mountain of God.
Whenever God would show up. Whatever mountain God was on, that was
the mountain of God. So, we just proclaim in this place.
This is the space where heaven can come because his spirit is
here with us. Amen. Do you believe this morning that the spirit
is still hovering over the waters and he's bringing order out of
chaos? How many believe that? So, let's just invite him here. Let's
invite the spirit to blow over us today. Whatever torment and violence
is in our lives, whatever chaos is happening, let's just take a
deep breath. Let the spirit begin to move over us this morning.
Father, we just invite you. Blow with your Holy Spirit over us
this morning.
Father, we just receive life this morning that comes from your throne.
We thank you for your dwelling presence with us. Not just in
our hearts but among us as a people. So we just speak
the presence of the Lord in this in this place. We receive
it. We just say, spirit, do your work in us this morning
to make us right and aligned with you. And all of the
priorities of heaven would become ours. All of the visions
and thoughts and imaginations of heaven would become ours this morning. So
let let's just enter into his presence as he fills this place
and bless his name. Amen.
God,
Father
Jesus Christ.
Calm
down.
Calm down.
I found the power.
Thank you Jesus. >> Sing praises to your name,
oh Lord. Praises to your name,
oh Lord,
for your name is great and greatly to
be praised.
I sing praises to your name,
oh Lord. Praises to your name,
oh Lord,
for your name is great and greatly to
be praised.
I sing glory. I sing glory to your name,
oh Lord. Glory to your name,
oh Lord,
for your name is great and greatly to
be praised.
I sing glory to your name,
oh Lord, glory to your name,
oh Lord,
for your name is great and greatly to
be praised.
I sing glory to your name,
oh Lord, glory to your name,
oh Lord,
for your name is great and greatly to
be praised.
I sing praises to your name,
oh Lord. Praises to your name,
>> oh Lord,
for your name is great and greatly
to be praised.
your name.
For your name is great and greatly
to be praised.
>> For your name, For your name is great and
greatly to be praised.
Jesus.
>> Jesus.
>> No name above your name.
>> Your name's above every other name.
I choose this day to be grateful, Lord.
I give you praise with an open heart. I'm waking
up to heaven.
I'm waking up to you.
I choose this day. I choose this day to be grateful.
Lord, I give you praise with an open heart.
I'm waking up to heaven.
I'm waking up to you. I'm waking up.
I'm waking up to you
for always being good. For always being good.
Thank you for your mercies that are new.
Thank you in spirit and in truth.
Thank you. I'm telling you, thank you. Your faithfulness,
your faithfulness
is like a sunrise.
Your endless love reaches past the skies. I'm waking
up to heaven.
I'm waking up to you. Your faithfulness, your faithfulness,
your faithfulness.
It's like a sunrise.
And let's fly
past the skies. I'm waking up to the
I'm waking up to you. Wake us up.
I'm waking up to heaven.
I'm waking up to you for always being good.
For always being good, we say thank you for
your mercies that are new every morning. Thank you
in spirit and in truth. Thank you. I'm telling
you, thank you for always being good.
For always being good. Thank you for
your mercies that are new. Thank Thank you
in spirit and in truth. Thank you. I'm telling
you. Thank you.
You and you alone. Awakening up my soul. And it's
my joy to thank you. Thank you
and you alone awaking up my soul. And it's
my joy to thank you and thank you
and you alone. The waking up my soul. It's
my joy to thank you. Thank you
and you alone for waking up our souls. And it's
our joy to thank you. We say thank you
for always being good. Thank you
for your mercies that are new. Thank you
in spirit and in truth. Thank you. I'm telling
you thank you.
We're telling you thank you. Tell him thank you.
We're telling you thank you. We've got so much to be thankful
for. I'm telling you, thank you for the breath in my lungs.
I'm telling you, thank you.
We're telling you, thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
We're telling you, thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you
for you and you alone. The waking up my soul.
>> And it's my joy.
It's our joy. It's our joy. You and you alone.
Waking up my soul. And it's my joy to thank you.
Thank you for you alone. >> You're waking up our
soul and it's our joy. Thank you.
Thank you. And you alone are waking up our
souls. And it's our joy to thank you.
Thank you. >> We're telling you thank you. >> We're telling you thank
you.
Oh Jesus. >> That's how we enter
with thanksgiving. >> Yeah. Come on. >> That's how we enter
with thanksgiving.
What a joy and a privilege. It's how we enter.
It's with thanksgiving.
What a joy. What a privilege. It's how we enter.
What a joy. What a privilege.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Overflowing.
Oh, we say thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Oh, we thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
>> We thank you. Thank you.
Oh, we thank you. Thank you.
>> We come in with thankful heart. We thank you. Thank you. >> Oh,
we thank you. Thank you. >> We thank you.
>> Come on. It's a good thing to posture our hearts. We're singing
out, "Thank you.
Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Heart full of praise.
Heart full of thanks
overflowing.
We say thank you.
Lord, we come in with humble, lowly hearts, Lord, to
just be in your midst. What an honor,
Lord. These aren't empty words. This is a history of thanksgiving.
Lord, we have so much to be thankful for.
>> There's testimony after testimony in this room. We've seen your faithful hand,
>> Lord. We say thank you for being here. Thank you for delivering
us. Thank you for saving us. Thank you for redeeming us. Thank
you for washing us clean, God. We thank you. There's so much
to be thankful for, church.
>> Thank you, God.
Lord, you're worthy of everything.
Worthy of every song we could ever sing.
Worthy of all the praise we could ever bring.
Worthy of every breath we could ever breathe. We live for you.
Sing it again. Worthy.
Worthy of every song we could ever sing.
Worthy of all the praise we could ever breathe.
Worthy of every breath we could ever breathe. We live for you.
>> Jesus. Sing Jesus the name.
Jesus the name above every other name.
Jesus the only one who could ever sing.
Worthy of every breath we could ever breathe. We live for you.
Oh, we live for you. Sing holy and holy. There
is no one like you. There is none beside you.
Open up my eyes in want to. Show me
who you are and fill me with your heart and lead me
in your love to those. Sing it again. Tell him and holy
there is no one like you. There is none beside you.
Open up my eyes in wonder. Show me
who you are and fill me with your heart and lead me
in your love to those around me.
Holy,
holy,
sing
worthy.
Worthy of every song we could ever sing.
Worthy of all the praise we could ever bring.
Worthy of every breath we could ever breathe. We live for you.
Oh, we live for you, Jesus.
Jesus, the name above every other name.
Jesus, the only one who could ever save.
Worthy of every breath we could ever breathe. We live for you.
Yeah. We live for you. Sing holy and holy. There
is no one like you. There is none beside you. Open
up my eyes.
You show me who you are and fill me with your heart
and lead me in your love to those. You are holy,
holy. There is no one like you. There is none beside
you. Open up our eyes in wonder. Show
me who you are and fill me with your heart and lead
in your love to those around me.
Won't you lead us?
Won't you lead us? Holy Spirit,
we are the leader. You are the leader. Oh, we follow the
leader. I will follow you for all my days.
>> Oh, I will follow you for all my days. I will follow
the leader. I am not the high priest. I am not the
high priest you are. I thank you God.
Let's sing this out. I will build my life.
I will build my life upon your
>> lift it up and I will put my trust in
you.
In I >> Come on, let's make this a prayer. Come on, press
in. I will my life upon
it is
>> you are the firm foundation
put my trust you are and I
will not you are holy holy There
is no one like you. There is none beside you. Open
up my eyes and wonder and show me who you
are and fail me with your heart and lead me in your
love. You are holy, holy, holy. There is
no one like you. There is none beside you. Open
up my eyes. Open up and show me who you
are and fill me with your heart and lead me in your
love. I will build I will build and I will build
my life upon your love. It is
a firm foundation and I will put
my trust in you
and I will not be shen.
>> Oh will not be shen. We will not be shaken. >> My firm
foundation. >> We have built our lives on this truth. >> My solid
rock which I stand. All other ground is shifting sand.
All other ground is sinking sand.
You're my solid rock.
My firm found. >> Yeah. >> My firm found.
>> Jesus.
I will build my life. Come on. Let's pray it. and I
will build my life upon your love.
It is a fat foundation.
And I will put my trust in you
alone. And I will not be shen.
Come on, lift up your own voice. >> Sing your own melody.
>> Come on, let's stand on this truth for a little bit. >> Come
on, minister to the king. Minister to the king, church. Come on.
You don't need us to lead you. You have your own voice.
Tell him, >> Lord, we will build our lives on this truth. >> I
build my life on the rock of Jesus. >> Build my life
upon this truth.
>> For my rock, my firm foundation.
So worthy is the lamb.
>> Seated on the throne.
>> We crown you now with many crowns.
You reign victorious.
us
and highly lifted up.
Jesus, son of God,
the talling of heaven crucified.
Worthy is the lamb. Come on, lift it up. Worthy.
Worthy is the lamb. Come on, let's keep singing this. Tell him,
"Worthy is the lamb. Worthy, worthy,
worthy is the lamb." One more time. Worthy,
worthy is the lamb.
Worthy, worthy is the lamb.
>> Sing. Worthy is the lamb and worthy is the lamb.
Come on, lift it up. See it on the throne.
We crown you now with many crowns.
You reign victorious
high and lifted up high and lifted up.
Jesus son of God. Jesus son of God.
The dwelling of heaven crucified.
Worthy, worthy. Worthy is the lamb.
Worthy, worthy is the lamb.
Sing it again. Worthy is the lamb. Worthy, worthy,
worthy is the lamb. Oh, let's sing it again. Worthy is the
lamb
and worthy is the lamb.
Seated on the throne.
We call you down.
You reign victorious
high. High and lifted up. Jesus.
Jesus. Son of God.
The darling of heaven who
worthy is the lamb.
Worthy is the lamb.
Worthy. Worthy is the lamb.
>> We give you glory, God.
>> Worthy of praise. >> We give you glory, God.
Honor and riches worth. >> There's none like you. There's none beside
you.
Oh, worthy is the lamb.
Oh, worthy is the Lamb.
Oh, worthy is the Lamb. I want to keep singing and tell
him, "Oh, worthy is the Lamb."
Worthy is the lamb.
Worthy is the
We love you.
Oh, we love you,
Jesus. We love you.
Oh, how we love you.
You are the one.
>> Our hearts to
Jesus we love. love you.
>> Oh, how we love you.
>> You are the one
I heart to adore.
We love you, God.
How
you love
how we love
how we
I was just in awe of his presence in this room. I
just feel the glory cloud just kind of swirling around. I mean,
if you're not sensing it, just lean into his presence. Just focus
on him.
And as we've committed oursel to build our life on you and
put oursel in that posture, it's you who are doing the building.
Father, we just submit to your your construction project in us to
heal us, to make us whole. Father, >> thank you for your building
project in each one of us. And as you work on each
one, Father, you're building us into a community. Father, those lights and
salts in the earth, Father, we glorify you in this place, Father.
All the titles that we've called you this morning, they're just loaded.
They're just loaded with meaning. >> And Father, we just acknowledge the King
in this place. We acknowledge the son of God.
>> The darling of heaven. >> We acknowledge the darling of heaven. >> That son
of God. Even the title is has kingship all loaded in there.
Father, we do crown you. We do crown you with our lives.
You have been crowned. And we crown you again and again and
again. and every crown that we would hope to receive, we throw
it at your feet, Father, as the elders are doing right in
this moment, Father. We lay every achievement in our life before you,
Lord, just as you have taken every wrong and every destruction. We
give you everything that we've done right, Father. It's all for you.
We humble ourselves before you and say, "It is all you. It
is all your grace this morning and we receive from you, Lord.
That completed work that's promised, we receive it right now. Thank you
for your rescue from darkness. But we know saving is something that's
happening right now. You are saving us >> and you will save these
bodies in the resurrection. But I thank you. I thank you for
right now in this moment, how you're moving and you're saving us.
Thank you, God, for your saving power that's in your name. You
are the one who saves. Thank you, God. Let's just receive that
saving power over us right now.
>> Thank you, God.
>> Bless you, Lord.
Jesus.
Oh, how
I know the spirit can continue to work despite our transitions, but
it's doesn't make it easy.
just let him continue to work in our hearts. Well, let's just
take a moment to love on one another, see the glory of
the Lord in each other, and give thanks for that. Embrace one
another. Amen.
I don't
How are you?
I don't know.
All right. Well, welcome back. I hope everyone feels thoroughly greeted this
morning. This is uh one of our highlights. Catch up and greet
one another. If this is your f first time, I I want
to welcome you here at Consume Church. And uh there's several ways
to connect with us. Either a card in the back or we'll
put up a QR code there if you are familiar with technology
and can just fill that out for us. We'd like to get
to know you. Um here at Consumed, uh we have several ways
to give and I just personally want to thank all of you
for your faithful giving. Um it's just a blessing to see your
generosity and uh we have an app that's uh called the church
center app is is probably the easiest way to do it. You
can also go to the website. Scanning the QR code will get
you there directly. And then we have a traditional box in the
back if you want to do it the oldfashioned way. And uh
we have a new tradition uh here at Consumed of actually declaring
over our giving that God would use this for the benefit of
the kingdom and all of the dynamic that goes into our giving
of ourselves to him. So I invite you to stand.
Let's just read this together. As we receive today's offering, we call
to mind our covenant membership in the Messiah. In the world, there
is never enough, but in him, we have no lack. In the
Messiah, we are inheriting all things. Our generosity is an expression of
our identity as God's children. To be like our generous father, we
give with good measure, pressed down, shaken together, and running over. We
freely give not from compulsion, but joyfully as an act of giving
loyalty. We declare that every part of our life belongs to him,
just as he has given all of himself to us. May the
sacrifices we give today be a sweet smelling aroma to diffuse the
fragrance of Christ in every place through the church to reveal his
kingdom, extend his freedom and impart new life until every enemy is
put under his feet. Hallelujah. Amen. Amen. Thank you. And one
of our themes this year is that Jesus is putting his enemies
under his feet and we're reclaiming ground this year. And it may
not feel that way. Um, I wasn't going to do this, but
Thursday I was taking advantage of the little bit cooler weather before
the inferno hits and uh was taking a hike and I was
listening to audio through uh uh Joshua and it said, "God will
go out as a hornet before you and destroy his enemies." And
right then a hornet probably three foot three inches long like this
started buzzing right in front of me and then circled around me
several times. that flew off and I think said, "Thank you, Lord.
Thank you, Lord." I mean, right that instant when I was hearing
that verse, >> this hornet showed up. I was like, "Thank you, God."
>> Yes. So, I don't know if there's omens or signs or anything
like that, but I I just took it as confirmation that the
Lord is going before us. So, uh, just to catch you up
on some of the activities, uh, we have our regular Wednesday night
flow service at 6:30 and the youth meet next door at 6:30
as well. Uh, come join us, be a part of that. Uh,
it's another opportunity to just drop into what the spirit is doing
and there is no junior holy spirit. So, we believe the youth
can do that as well. And that's one thing listening to the
Old Testament is like how things can change in one generation. >> Amen.
>> Either for the good or the bad. So let's let's pray this
generation. >> We see that marked turnaround in them. We're always speaking to
that end. But uh we've got to be faithful. Even us old
guys, right? Continue the march to the end. So uh those are
the two ones uh during the week. Uh we also have Friday
night twice a week. It's the first and third Friday night for
the young adults. So, come join that if you're in that demographic.
Uh we also have a community impact and I got a couple
announcements about that. So, we've been meeting second and fourth Saturdays
uh once usually to kind of just rally together, but the the
last Saturday of the month is usually to actually be in the
community and minister. and we've been passing out uh groceries uh to
some families in our mobile home park here locally. So, if you
didn't know that, that's what we've been about. And we may wind
that part of it down for the summer. We'll see. And and
engage in some other things. But before school starts here, it's right
up on us. We want to try to kick off this back
to school rally for those families specifically in that area. We've we've
had brief contact with many of them and some of them have
even more intimate uh relationship with us and he actually came to
Freedom Reigns. Uh and there's a lot of families with a bunch
of kids. So just pray about supporting into this. It's our outreach,
right? Our outreach tab. Uh, so, uh, what I've looked at is
about $80 to give one kid, uh, a good pack of supplies
that are general to all elementary grades. So, we've done some of
that logistic work. Uh, when we deliver groceries this next Saturday, we'll
get a final count of how many families want to do that.
Uh, but in the meantime, you can join us in praying for
that and giving in to that. We sure would appreciate it. Amen.
Amen. I just want to bless our community and a real tangible
way and serve them. So, I think that's it for now. I
I want to do a little something a little bit different. Uh,
Pastor John, come on up.
I just publicly want to speak a blessing over Pastor John this
morning. He alone knows all of the behind the scenes and the
challenges this year and the stuff that he carries.
Let's just uh extend your hands to him and just speak a
blessing over him and this morning as well, but just in general.
Father, I was just seeing this morning how you just desire to
hold John in the cliff of the rock and just expose yourself
and shine upon John this morning and in this season, Father, and
lighten the load that he's carried. Father, we just bless him as
a shepherd over the over this flock, over over this people, God,
uh to be upheld like Aaron and hold his arms up in
that rally of what you're doing in this place. And Father, we
just call upon your strength. We call upon your endurance on his
life and encouragement over his heart, Lord. So, just bless his word
this morning. Um, bless his mind, bless his heart, Lord, to communicate
all the things he has for us this morning in Jesus name.
Amen. Amen. Yeah.
Well, thank you all of you for that. That's very encouraging. And
Allan, it's so wonderful to see you just thriving in your gifting.
And and guys, we we are so blessed to have Allen's leadership
as he uh is leading out into uh this community impact initiative
to take that heart of an evangelist and and to really uh
love our neighbors and um so Allan, thank you for taking initiative
and doing all that stuff. So um I'm excited about what God's
going to do in and through our church. It seems like every
time we start something evangelistic or something new, it takes a little
while for people to really buy in. And is this for real?
Is this going to last? Are these guys just coming up with
something extra for us to do? Are we really going to make
a difference in the world? And uh I know that Allan believes
in outreach with everything that is in him from like the fiber
of his being. So otherwise, God bless you for championing uh that
expression of the body of Christ and out of this house. So
all right. Well, good morning. It's good to see you guys. Uh,
Pastor Matthew is visiting family in California. Some of you know of
some of the going on in his life in the last several
months and it's um just a real blessing and opportunity for him
to be with his family. So, we're thankful for that and uh
father just keep doing a mighty work in him and in his
family in Jesus name.
So today I was thinking about um how I have a a
visitor, a guest here from Italy. He was in the room. I
don't see him. But uh it's it's funny how often we're able
to see ourselves through the eyes of someone else. uh maybe sometimes
more sharply and clearly than we're used to because uh you know
we get familiar with the way in which we do life but
um having been to Italy and seeing how things are thousands of
years old and all built out and the culture generally is much
slower paced. It's like things are already built. You're not changing those
streets. You're not changing those roads. I how many of you would
like for us to get to a place where our roads are
like done?
>> I know I would. But it's funny to take them into a
a grocery store and you know, I I think we don't realize
how much different it is here from the rest of the world.
You know, we say that things that are bigger in Texas. Everything's
bigger in Texas. But North Texas, we're known for big stuff, right?
Big stores, big trucks, big dreams. Yeah. Big big churches, big
highways, and lately big traffic, big growth. How about this one? Big
data centers. If you y'all even notice that like what is that
massive weird looking building? It's a data center. Big expectations, big cost
of living. Every year more people come here chasing opportunity.
Did you guys realize this is one of the fastest growing areas in
the whole entire world populationwise? North Texas is rapidly approaching 9 million
people residents. >> Yep. And with all of that expansion comes longer commutes,
faster development, and increasing pressure on daily life. Has anybody I Oh,
thank you.
>> Has anybody noticed that? >> Yes. >> But here's what I've noticed. Most of
us don't need another opportunity. We need another hour.
We don't need another promotion. We need another breath.
>> Have you noticed how we're connected to everyone and yet truly connected
to no one? People feel lonier today than ever, being more connected
than ever. AI systems in their pressure to make every part of
our lives perfect and more efficient are rapidly changing the face of
how we do everything. Am I having trouble here?
>> Sorry, technical difficulties. Let me try this. How's that? The standard of
excellence and the speed at which things keep evolving is dizzying. It's
like everything has changed. If you're not keeping up with the latest
trends, it's almost like you feel like you're in a vacuum or
in a dark room all alone. I don't know if you've noticed
that yet, but six months ago, a year ago, we were talking
about AI. What's this going to do to our world? I think
we're finding out. In a matter of seconds, we're spitting out more
content than any human could possibly absorb or consume. It seems there's
no arena of life that is untouched by this relentless pursuit of
growth and perfection.
The pressure to keep up is real.
This is the kicker. Christians are now turning to technology and social
media for spiritual formation.
We are it's it's easy just to flip on a podcast or
download a sermon or whatever on the go. Opportun while there's opportunities
slow down enough for real disciplehip have almost completely vanished.
We have built lives with no margin. Look familiar? We have filled
every margin and then wonder why we have no room for God,
community or rest. Our culture tells us to maximize every moment. Work
more, buy more, experience more, scroll more. But a life,
a full life isn't necessarily a meaningful life.
>> Consumerism tells us we need more. Social media tells us everyone else
is doing more. So we keep adding while losing our peace, our
presence, and our attention.
When life gets too busy, the life of the church begins to
feel optional. It's true.
Gathering happens only when nothing else is scheduled. I I never thought
I would see a time when that was the case. But it's
here, guys. This is unprecedented times that we live in. I believe
community has become secondary. Jesus gets whatever margin remains. And that margin
is getting ever ever so tight and thin. So what is margin?
We'll talk about margin. Margin is the space between our load and
our limits. It's the white space on a page. It's the shoulder
on the highway. It's the emergency fund in your budget, the buffer
in your calendar. Get this. Without margin, every inconvenience becomes a crisis.
You ever feel that way? overreacting to things. Without margin, every
interruption becomes an irritation.
Don't have time for that right now. Without margin, every delay becomes
anger.
Without margin, every needy person becomes an obstacle.
So, the problem isn't that we're busy. Jesus was busy. He was
always busy. problem is we're busy without boundaries.
>> Gonna refer to John Mark Comr. G he he says Jesus was
never in a hurry. One of the strangest things about Jesus is
how unhurried he is. Think about it. People are dying.
Crowds are waiting. Demons are screaming. Religious leaders are plotting murder. And
Jesus, he just walks.
He stops for children.
He notices birds. He attends weddings.
He takes naps. Glory to God. Can I get an amen?
He disappears to lonely places to be with the father.
John Mark Comr says this, "Hurry isn't merely an external pace. It
reshapes the kind of people we become."
I know. I used to be the efficiency king. Some folks that
work for me, they'll tell you, you get that guy on the
tools and he's a different person. Look out.
The gospels reveal that Jesus refuses to let urgency become his master.
Jesus had enough margins to notice Zakius. He had enough margin to
bless children. He had enough margin to stop for a bleeding woman
while a little girl had died and he was about to raise
her from the dead. Love requires margin. We cannot love at highway
speed.
>> So in this day and age, in this culture, guys, this is
for real. I get it. I mean, I'm a part of it.
I feel it. What are the people of God to do? Surely,
this can't be the way that this turns out. That the church
just dries up. There are other countries where there are empty church
buildings everywhere for decades. Nobody in them. That's starting to happen here
in America. Churches are closing like crazy. But this problem isn't a
new problem. This is an ancient problem. We may have new technology
and new challenges, but it's the same spirits that we face. And
God has always had an answer. Anyone want to guess? Sabbath.
>> What are we doing about Sabbath? You got to know I'm preaching
to me more than anybody.
>> Reading my own mail. Let's look at some scripture. Uh, Exodus
20 verse 8.
Read the underlines with me.
Remember the Sabbath day. By the way, we're jumping in the middle
of the ten commandments. Remember the Sabbath day to keep it holy.
Six days you shall labor and do all your work, but the
seventh day is the Sabbath of the Lord your God. In it
you shall do no work. You nor your son, nor your daughter,
nor your male servant, nor your female servant, nor your cattle, nor
your stranger who is within your gates. For in six days the
Lord made the heavens and the earth, the sea, and all that
is in them, and rested the seventh day. Therefore, the Lord blessed
the Sabbath day and hallowed it.
I'm going to admit that the Sabbath is often misunderstood. I think
it has been for probably centuries. But Sabbath was never about a
rule. It wasn't just a religious practice. It was not even just
about rest. It's about identity.
It's about who they were as the people of God. as we
see in that first uh example of the ten commandments and then
over and over and over again in Leviticus and Deuteronomy as well
as Exodus, the Lord explains this as a reminder that they belonged
to the one true God, the creator God who himself rested on
the seventh day. was a way for them to identify themselves, to
be a part of the covenant, to be a part of God
himself. His special people meant that they emulated God, that God himself
rested, that's why they rested.
We're going to do a little bit of a dive on the
Sabbath here. Is everybody okay with that? >> It's been a while. I
don't know that I've spoke on this in a while. Maybe never.
I don't know. identity. It was a way for the people of
God to be like God in their work,
in their vocation,
their purpose in the earth. The commandment is not just that the
Israelites themselves were taking a break for the sake of taking a
break, but that those among them, their servants, their children, the stranger,
the foreigners, the animals, all of them experienced God's generous heart
through them as a people
to have leadership over them that was good to them. and not
a slave driver like what they'd experienced in Egypt to set a
holy example to testify of who God is by
his people exercising grace.
I've never looked at it like this before. Sabbath was observed as
a sign of who they were as the people of God.
Let's look at Exodus 31.
He says quite clearly right here, "Speak also to the children of
Israel, saying, Surely my Sabbath you shall keep, for it is a
sign between me and you throughout your generations, that you may know
that I am the Lord who sanctifies you." So this is bigger
than just getting a break or some random rule because you need
a nap. It's a bigger thing than that. answer. It's I am
going to identify forever. You will stand out in the earth throughout
all generations as my people to reflect my nature and my character
as not a slave driver but one who gives rest and promises
rest.
Now this for them was a radical shift in thinking. Think about
it. going from being slaves under hard labor, no identity, no value,
only what they could produce
to becoming godlike stewards of creation to act like God himself who
in the words of Jesus gives rest.
Let's look at some New Testament. Matthew 11 starting in verse 25.
I apologize for cramming so much on one page. It's an object
lesson in margin. It's not comfortable to read, right? Matthew 11:25-30.
At that time, Jesus turned to God with this prayer. I I
put so much on here because we always jump straight to the
take my yoke upon you. My burden is light. But it's connected
to this statement that he makes here about identity and about God's
personality, God's character. At that time, Jesus turned to God with his
prayer. I give you my praise. Everybody say it. Father, >> master of
heaven and earth. Master of heaven and earth. Master is a term
for boss. Father. So, we have a boss. Jesus is identifying his
boss, his leader, the one in charge of his vocation as a
father,
master of heaven and earth. You hid these things from the wise
and intelligent and what? Revealed them to children. Meaning that
it is hard in a employee employer relationship to ascertain
and to see who God is without understanding this element of being
a part of the family of having a loving father. Yes, father.
That's the way you decided to do it. My father gave me
everything. Nobody knows the son except the father. And nobody knows the
father except the son and anyone the son wants to reveal him
to. Now, let me just say something about that for a minute
because as a business owner and as a pastor, in many ways,
I hope that I exude the heart of the father, but in
many ways, people might know me in the way that they know
me based on a business relationship, but my children and those that
walk with me closely know that I'm maybe a little bit different
in the way in which I relate to people. I hope. Lord,
help me.
There's something very special that Jesus is saying here about our vocation
and our purpose and our work that is connected to this idea
of rest is knowing God as a really good boss as a
dad. All right. Are you having a real struggle? Come to me. Are
you carrying a big load on your back? Come to me. I'll
give you a rest. Pick up my yoke and take it on.
take lessons from me, I'll be gentle with you. Jesus is talking
about his work. Often when we preach this, we talk about taking
a nap or something, but Jesus is actually talking about the way
in which we approach our vocation, our purpose, our destiny in God,
the way in which we exist to find meaning in the things
that we do. Pick up my yoke and take it on. Take
lessons from me. I'll be gentle with you. The last thing in
my heart is to give you a hard time. You'll see. Rest
you need and rest you shall have. It almost sounds like the
Yoda version or something, but my yoke is easy to wear and
my load is easy to bear. This is the Kingdom Translation, Kingdom
New Testament. I love it. So, we see that Jesus is emulating
and showing us the Father. This is what he's saying. I'm showing
you the Father. He's gentle and humble as a boss. He's not
the kind of master that is driving us hard to judging every
mistake, never giving us a break.
He doesn't overload his employees. He carries it alongside of us. Jesus
is revealing this heart of the father in love and compassion especially
in our vocation so that all may delight in the work of
their hands just like the father did.
I I'd have to say that
for the last decade or so, my understanding of maybe even longer
of the Sabbath was kind of grounded in Jesus's approach to the
Sabbath seemed to be not nonchalant, but almost against the Sabbath. He
was constantly doing things that people wanted to kill him for because
he wasn't practicing the Sabbath. He would heal on the Sabbath. He
made statements about being the Lord of the Sabbath.
He seemed like he was disregarding it and blowing it up, but
he was actually defining the Sabbath.
I want to read a story here in Mark chapter 2 where
we see that Jesus actually gets angry at the hardness of the
hearts of the Pharisees because of the irony of them judging him
for breaking the Sabbath and them not even understanding what it's about.
Let's look at Mark 2. Lots of scripture today
again from the Kingdom New Testament. One Sabbath Jesus is walking through
the corn fields. His disciples made their way along plucking corn as
they went. "Look here," said the Pharisees to him, "why are they
doing something illegal on the Sabbath?" "Haven't you read what David did?"
replied Jesus. when he was in difficulties and he and his men
got hungry, he went into God's house. Uh this is when Abiar
was high priest and ate the bread of the presence which only
the priests were allowed to eat. Read the underline. And he gave
it to the people with him. The Sabbath was made for humans,
he said, not humans for the Sabbath. So the son of man
is master even of the Sabbath. News about him spread swiftly throughout
the entire region of Galilee.
What verse is that? Oh, we're going right into chapter three. Sorry.
Chapter three. Because verse 28 is the last verse of the chapter.
Chapter 3. Once more Jesus went to the synagogue. There was a
man there with a withered hand. People were watching to see if
Jesus would heal him on the Sabbath so that they could frame
a charge against him. Stand up, said Jesus, to the man with
the withered hand and come out here. And he said to them,
looking over to the Pharisees, "Is it lawful to do good on
the Sabbath or to do evil, to save life or to kill?"
talk about reading your mail because their whole point in being a
part of this conversation was they were looking to kill him. They
stayed quiet. He was deeply upset at their hard-heartedness. And he looked
round at them angrily. Then he said to the man, "Stretch out
your hand." He stretched it out and his hand was restored. >> Hallelujah.
The Pharisees went out right away and began to plot with the
Herodians against Jesus, trying to find a way to destroy him.
We see here that the Sabbath is given to facilitate a healthy
stewardship of creation. It's a way for the people of God and
really all humanity to look back and be thankful for the way
in which God was working together with them to create, to develop,
to bless one another, to bless God, to reflect and see God
at work in the productivity and creativity that we exhibited throughout the
week. What I mean, talk about a a shift in perspective.
What would it be like for us instead of feeling like we're
trying to catch up all the time, be at a place where
we have a full stop and turn around and enjoy everything that
God's done.
Celebrate it. I mean, that's what we're supposed to be doing. This
practicing the rest of God actually stands in stark contrast to a
world that can never get enough.
The world is always focused on what is lacking, always dissatisfied, constantly
searching for meaning, protection, and self-preservation. Guys, that we don't have to
worry about that stuff.
I I think what happens for us as believers is we start
to get caught up in the flow of the culture because it
it does it impacts almost everything. gas pump, price
of groceries,
just staying keeping your business afloat.
God's people have been set apart, redeemed to be a whole different
species. Did you know that you're a new type of human being
identified in Jesus himself, defined in Jesus, the God type of human?
By giving us the Holy Spirit, he's given us the ability to
be fully yolked with him.
Get this one. When we overwork, we express an unhealthy desire to
be little g godlike
instead of being like God as he has revealed himself.
So God rests on the seventh day, not because he's exhausted, but
because he takes up his rest.
God isn't tired. He isn't plopping down on the couch, throwing up
his hands, can't do anymore. No, he's beginning to rain. He takes
up his rest. He's beginning to rain from his completed creation, from
a sense of his good.
It's not God giving up or taking a break. It's God saying,
"It's finished. Now, let's enjoy what I've made." So, Tim Mackey points
out that Sabbath is actually woven into the very fabric of creation
before it becomes a part of Israel's law. The rhythm, I'm sorry,
the rhythm becomes the command, which means humans were created not just
to produce, but to delight.
>> I I remember there was a a season in my life where
I had um never made so much money and lived so little.
I I can't believe it, but I I got caught up in
a company had bought the company that I worked at and my
rhythm got all messed up and uh they would hand you a
a list every week and say, "You have to get this list
done. We don't care how you do it." Well, it seemed like
because of their system, it was next to impossible. And it it
wound up being a situation where everybody was up there working till
10 o'clock at night, at least two weeks, the last two weeks
of the month, trying to get the quota. But I noticed that
we started working Saturdays and then we started working Sundays, trying to
keep up with this never-ending list of stuff. And I made a
little bit more money. I'm talking like maybe 5% more money, but
I had like 2% of the life I used to have. I
remember we went we went camping, which is what we used to
do once a month back in those days when we were raising
the kids. I I went camping. That that was our time to
kick back and just look at the fruit of our labors and
say, "Wow, you know, we earned a little time off, three-day weekend
or whatever." And um I remember going and I was so tired.
All I did is slept in the camper. Boat sat outside the
camper. Didn't do a thing. Seriously, I thought I have no energy
for anything. Anything other than keeping up with that hamster wheel.
So Sabbath is not just about identity. It's about resistance.
Entright points it out like this. He says, "For Jews in Jesus's
world, the Sabbath was a badge of Jewishness for people who'd been
persecuted and killed just for being Jewish.
It was a national flag that spoke of freedom to come, of
hope for the great day of rest that was promised by God
when he would finally liberate Israel from pagan oppression. It looked back
to the creation of the world to the Exodus and it marked
out those people who kept it as God's special people, his faithful
people, his loving people, his hoping people. The whole point of the
commandment was celebrating God's creation, his redemption, both past, present, and
future. That's a pretty big deal because we talk about our own
hope. The promises of scripture is that Jesus will return and everything
that is heavy will be no more. We will be liberated from
bondage and from slavery and we will actually set all of creation
free and the power and presence the spirit of God will be
everywhere.
>> It's what we're waiting for. Lately, I've been uh talking about some
perspectives from eaten bar. As you can imagine, he has some things
to say about the Sabbath. But he was saying that it's not
simply a Jewish custom. It was Israel's declaration that Pharaoh no longer
owned them. For 400 years, their value came from bricks, quota, output,
production.
Sound familiar? Today, our pharaoh does not carry a whip. He sends
notifications, >> measures productivity, rewards availability.
>> He whispers, "You are what you accomplish."
>> Listen, every time you refuse to stop, you're declaring that Pharaoh still
has authority.
So every Sabbath is an act of holy rebellion, resistance. Exodus
20.
And God spoke all these words, saying, I am the Lord your
God, who brought you out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. You shall have no other gods before me.
You shall not make for yourself a carved image, for I, the
Lord your God, am a jealous God. Now, I cut a little
bit of it out. You probably know that uh verse seven says,
you shall not take the name of the Lord your God in
vain. There's this passion in the Lord's heart about, hey, I've married
you guys. Like, I've made myself part of you and you part
of me. There is a special thing that God has done, decided
to do with his people. Not to reign from above, dictate down
here. No, to come and be present in our midst, to be
a participant in what's going on in the earth. And as he's
done this, he's revealed himself in his goodness and his faithfulness and
his loving kindness and his mercies that never cease. And of course,
this is the beginning of the Ten Commandments, but often it's not
so much a bunch of dos and don'ts without us seeing the
heart of God in here. He does not want to be associated
with gods of Egypt. You shall have no other god before me.
Before me, that's doesn't register with us. We think, okay, well, let's
not put idols in here. Well, yeah, that's yeah, that's true. But
he doesn't want to compete with some other thing ruling your life.
It was a a little bit more blatant and obvious in that
day because there was the cultures around them had other gods. They
were very in touch with their other gods. But their other gods
character and their forms of worship were very dehumanizing, very
cold, very hard,
brutal, oppressing.
To me, the commandments reveal a hard reset in the heart and
mind of the people of God to discern the character and nature
of God as opposed to any other God. These relational dynamics reveal
a sharp contrast between who he is and who they are.
talking about difference. Let's look at Exodus 23.
Six days you shall do your work, and on the seventh day
you shall rest, that your ox and your donkey may rest, and
the son of your female servant and the stranger may be refreshed.
And in all that I have said to you, this is a
kicker, be circumspect and make no mention of the name of other
gods, nor let it be heard from your mouth.
So much of what we see is just hard and fast rules
is the Lord being like, I'm not going to share you with
some other god that is trying to destroy you. I've gone through
all this effort to deliver you and to make you this special
wonderful people.
I don't know. It seems like
seems like today we've lost touch with the essence of the Ten
Commandments. I don't even know that they're honored like they used to
be. I think they're bringing them back like in Oklahoma, but when
I was a kid, the Ten Commandments were on the wall in
every public school. It's just a normal normal thing. Churches would have
them up or whatever. I think in and even in a lot
of popularized preaching, we kind of do this law versus grace thing
and it's a easy way to kind of ignore the Ten Commandments.
But the ten commandments, if we're seeing the heart and mind of
God in them, it's just his like left story of how to
work together, how to live together.
You see, this desire of God's heart, don't even talk about those
other gods. So much of what we are shocked at in the
Old Testament has everything to do with this idolatry and with other
gods. There's this war for this middle earth, if I could use
that term, this second heaven. I've heard people use that term. uh
not the heaven where God reigns, but this space in the spirit
that seems to interfere with what we do on earth and affect
and influence the things that we do that has plagued us from
like Genesis 6 on and uh God's saying, I am going to
make a special people and set you apart and make you holy
and make you part of myself. And now he's like fully and
totally done that by breathing the life of the spirit into us.
Aren't you thankful?
>> So there's a difference between getting ahead and being ahead in
our work. sounded clever when I wrote it, but there's a difference
between getting ahead or trying to get ahead and actually being the
head in our work. I I remember working for the man for
like 20 years. And somewhere in the middle of there, I had
no idea that what I was learning how to do was to
serve well. Not just serve the man, but serve everyone around me.
God changed me completely changed who I am in that season.
I I think that there's something that God is working into the
heart of all of us to learn how to lead from a
place of humility and gentleness
so that we can reflect
his nature, his character to the rest of the world, to one
another but to the rest of the world. This is the point
of us taking up rest
is so that others will be able to see who God really
is. Am I making sense?
Margin also reveals who we trust. So here's the uncomfortable question.
Why don't we slow down?
We often say, "I'm too busy. I don't have time to fill
in the blank. But maybe that's not really true. Maybe we're too
afraid. Afraid we'll fall behind.
Afraid someone else will get ahead. I used to be bad about
this. I'd get on the road and, you know, go, "Don't you
pass me."
I can't believe how delivered I am from that these days. You
know, it's because I'm older or something. Unless I'm having a bad
day.
Are we afraid that business will suffer?
I remember becoming a highly efficient, highly effective machine at work. And
if I'm being honest, some of that motivation was just like, I
don't know if God's going to quite handle this, but I'll work
with him to make sure that we don't get behind, get a
little extra. I'll let God sort that out, but I'm I remember
feeling that feeling.
Maybe we're afraid the kids won't make the team or that we
won't be able to give them everything that we didn't ever get.
Kids can be a powerful and discovering grandkids can be a powerful
motivator to do things that put you in a bind.
Maybe we're afraid that our future depends entirely on us.
And Sabbath asks one terrifying question. Do we really think that he's
not able to take care of our needs, to sustain us,
and to redefine us as his people? That's really, guys, I mean,
it's where the rubber hits the road. And like I said, I'm
preaching to me more than to anyone else probably. So why do
we need margin?
Oh my gosh. Some of us have built lives that would really
impress Pharaoh. Move you right up to the top in the slave
list. We leave before sunrise. We fight traffic. Answer emails
in the pickup line. Listen to podcasts at one and a half
speed. Watch Netflix while checking Slack.
Pray while folding laundry. I've had seasons where the commute. That was
my prayer time. It's not wrong. It's good. Get it where you
can. And wonder why you can't hear God's voice, though. I don't
think it's because God's speaking less. How many of you know God's
always speaking? But a repeated thing I I hear is people like,
"Man, I'm not sure. I haven't heard the Lord's voice in a
long time." I don't think it's because he's speaking less. It's probably
because we've got more noise going on than ever.
>> Silence isn't empty. It's often where we hear God speak. >> You need
some.
>> I miss our condo. I used to have a place at the
lake and it was so quiet out there. I could hear the
synapses in my brain firing.
The enemy loves hurry. Prosperity isn't wrong. It's not evil. Technology isn't
evil. Ambition's not wrong or evil. But anything that leaves no room
for God, for your spouse, for your children, for your neighbors, or
even your own soul becomes spiritually dangerous.
Satan doesn't always tempt us to sin. He doesn't have to. Sometimes
he's just trying to wear us out,
distract us from our purpose and our calling.
So, as we looked at Jesus's invitation to remind us of that
invitation in Matthew 11, come to me. Come to me all who
are weary. Notice what he doesn't say. He doesn't say, "Come to
me who are weary and I'll give you better time management."
He doesn't offer life hacks.
He offers himself. his life, his vocation. He's offering us a
job himself as your boss.
You're like, John, you always talk about this. Well, maybe it's not
always easy to hear. Jesus is offering us employment in the family
of God.
I think when we begin to understand and embrace the offer that
he's extending to us, we're going to discover that he's the best
boss ever.
There, you know, the place I worked at for 20 years where
I'd gotten highly efficient was awesome. It was God. His hand was
on it. But when he finally said, "Hey, it's time to go."
And I thought, Lord, I'm making more money than I've ever made.
This can't be God. And I told Lauren and she said, "Oh,
yeah, it's the Lord." I thought, "Oh, no. It's God."
It took me a year. I was so caught up in in
my cycle. It was so had become so a part of who
I was. I just couldn't quite swallow it. That was a hard
year. I knew it was the Lord, but I just couldn't couldn't
get bring myself to I told this to Duncan Smith once. He
said, 'Are you always that slow to obey the Lord? Are you
always that disobedient? Maybe that was how he said it.
Not anymore. I learned my lesson. But I did not realize how
much of my value, how much of my personality, how much of
who I was was tied up. And really the person that I
had developed that was this super efficient machine-like ultimate
I was a automotive technician. Didn't realize how h how much value
and worth I derived from hey everybody knows that you got a
problem with your car and you don't go anywhere because this guy's
going to take care of it and fast.
I remember when the Lord said, "It's time to go." And I
finally left. Y'all have heard me talk about this, but it was
like somebody cut all my wires. I I mean, internally, I I
thought I was going to freak out. I thought, "I don't even
know how to feel, how to think, how to be, and the
Lord was just like, I've got you." I remember driving to we
had rented a little building for our first business. Didn't even know
what I was doing. I was just following the voice of God.
driving there just crying my eyes out because I said you're killing
me. You're literally killing me right now. He was I mean who
I thought I was. He was murdering. I had no idea. Dropped
me down in this little boat dealership where all the guys sit
around and talk about fish. And inside I'm flipping out. I'm like
we production needs to happen like right now. Like how how is
everybody just like well I guess we'll get to that tomorrow or
Thursday.
And the Lord was like, "Yep, this is your life now." I
thought, "No, I'm going to die." I got to be honest with
you, you know, as you guys get used to me as your
pastor. I still have a wiring inside of me that will get
with it. I can get with it. But I'm so thankful that
that's not my personality. That's not the strongest part of my personality.
I discovered I couldn't believe it. God was so good to me.
Couldn't believe it.
I discovered I thought, "Oh, no. Everything's going to get behind." Oh,
no. I discovered we didn't miss anything. Never missed a bill. I
remember with fear and trembling going, "God, okay, I trust you, but
I don't know what I'm going to do." I said, "I guess I'm
going to have to give up all the things." And I mean,
we live below our means. This is margin, right? We had lived
below our means for a long time, but for some reason, I
still felt like I had to do all this extra. And the
Lord specifically said, "Your quality of life will not change one bit."
All I could do is just trust him.
I'm not telling you guys to go quit your job. I know
it's tempting. Work is not evil. God created us for work. It's
our approach to work that God is trying to break off of
us. Y'all understand what I'm saying?
>> The deepest margin won't be found in your planner. It'll be found
in his presence with his people in community working for his purposes.
That's what God was giving me. He was breaking me and giving
me the ability to have lots of margin to do the stuff
that he called me to do. This
So let's get practical
right now in this day and age in this location. The fastest
growing place on the planet I believe. How are we going to
adjust to the break neck speed at which the goalpost keeps moving?
It's hard just to live here. I remember having friends 15 years
ago that had to move to Oklahoma just to be able to
afford to pay rent.
I am figuring this out, too. I I'm just going to be
honest. As a pastor, there were seasons in our life where where
Lauren had just said, "Hey, here's your boundaries. Say no to moving
people.
It's a hard no. You're not moving anybody. You can't get hurt.
But I remember having created like boundaries in in life. There were
seasons in my life where I did that well. And even now
in ministry, I I'm trying to figure it out, too. I mean,
I'm walking through this with you guys in our culture and trying
to figure out what does it look like. So, please don't hear
any judgment in me. I'm inviting us. I believe God is inviting
us all to take a look at where we're at and say,
"You know what? Some things never change." Like God's invitation for us to
time out, spend time with me, spend time with my family. Redirect
your whole entire wiring about why you do the things that you
do. Amen. So, how about if this week we did something like
go a whole day without your phone? Can you even remember the
last time you went a day without your cell phone? Full-on panic
mode. Happened to me last year in Italy. That was not a
good place to be without my phone. Didn't speak the language.
How about eating a meal slowly?
Maybe for you it looks like sitting down with your family and
having a meal like we used to. That's not traditional. That's like
holy. It's sacred time.
Speaking of which, can we have the elements? Let's Let's have a
holy meal together. What do you say?
How about walking around without earbuds? Does anybody do this?
We're just pumping in podcasts, maybe jokes, I don't know, the latest commentary
on how to be cool. I'm young. I'm old, so that doesn't
apply to me too much. But I've noticed for young people, they
watch and listen to all this ways in which they're training themselves
to be cool, you know, to stay relevant with the culture. So
for you young people, maybe a day with no earbuds.
How about if we read scripture or read something about scripture without
multitasking?
Or if this is just, hey, you know what? I'm spending time
in the word of God today. Get up early. You can't sleep
anyways. You're too stressed out.
Just go on ahead and get up and read the word. Spend
some time talking to the Lord. How about saying no to something
good? Something good that you know you really don't have time for.
This is me. I say no to you. Please know that I
love you. I'm not going to say no to you. But
say no to something good so you can say yes to someone
better, namely the Lord.
This this I think is the way that we can practice the
Sabbath without being legalistic
because the last thing we want to do is what the Pharisees
did and begin to take that sign of the covenant and turn
it into a sign for something else. Snobby people, rude people, nationalistic
people, thankful for America. That's not what I'm saying. But it can
become a badge of something that other than God's personality himself.
Can we practice the Sabbath as trust and identity,
not just some kind of rule, but like this is who I
am. This is an indicator that goes against the culture. This is
who we are as the people of God. I don't know. To
me, that's a little different than I've ever seen it. Practice the
Sabbath as part of your vocation.
Part of this greater hope and expectation that we're declaring that God
will give us the rest that he's promised.
The future world that he's promised us is coming. And we are
taking time out. We don't care what the world thinks because we're
celebrating that reality. You guys, if you look like in in the
book of Leviticus, I didn't have it in here, but I'm thinking
somewhere around 20, there's this promise. If you will keep the Sabbath,
your land will flourish, your animals will increase in number. You'll have
peace. The sword won't come against you. You won't even have to
look over your shoulder. you'll be at rest. There's something about the
way that God designed this to work that flows with all of
creation. It's only when we start practicing the ways of the other
gods that we get ourselves into these jams. Yeah. I'm asking you
to go against the grain, against the culture. Who's with me?
Well, let's have this meal together.
So Jesus, we thank you for your body.
Lord, we so identify with your flesh that our bodies are also
union unified with your body. Lord, the way we spend our time,
the places that we go, we just surrender to embodying you. Take
the bread with me.
And Lord, we thank you.
We thank you that you have loaded history
and given us a way for us to remember. You said to
do this in remembrance of you. We thank you for this cup,
Lord. We thank you that we all drink into this cup which
is your life,
Lord. We step back into covenant, not legalism at all, Lord. And
I thank you that your life is not burdensome. It's not heavy.
Lord, we bring to you in this moment all of our weariness,
our toil and our exhaustion, our anxiety and our stress. We just
release it. We let go.
We thank you, God, that you have washed us in your blood.
Take the cup with me.
So Lord, as we go, we just offer up our lives. God,
we pray that throughout this week and over the next month and
year that we hear the voice of the spirit calling us to
rest, to step into our identity, to understand our purpose in you,
Lord. Thank you. What what an honor it is to be called
your children.
Hallelujah.
If you've been watching online, God bless you. Thank you for joining
us.
Thank you guys for listening.
Now you know, now you can hold me accountable.
How's pastor getting rest?
Love you guys. If we can agree with you in prayer, if
there's sickness in your body, if you're struggling in your finances or
if this message has shaken you up and irritated you in any
way, please call me. Set set an appointment. We'll go to lunch.
We'll talk about it. Bless y'all.
Thank you.